

AFSHAN SHAHID

0333-0240912 director hr1989@yahoo.com Flat NO.34, 4th Floor, Dada Terrace, Jamal Uddin Afghani Road, Bahadurabad, Karachi

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS / CERTIFICATIONS

- Certificate of Appreciation as In-House Trainer Lucky Textile Mills Ltd,
- Certification Train the Trainer. Lucky Textile Mills Ltd,
- Building Word Power TRC (Teacher's Recourse Center),
- Certification in Personality Grooming (HR) Mohammad Ali Jinnah University,
- Certification Empowerment for Life (HR) SOLF (School of Leadership Foundation),
- Certification in Equity Investment Management CSI (Canadian Securities Institute),
- Certification in MBTI Personality Test (Discover Yourself)-HR Intellect Consultants.
- Participation certificate as Organizer in WWF Carnival 2012 (WORLD WIDE FUND FOR NATURE PAKISTAN)
- Certification in Information Technology (CIT) Academy of Business Computers,

KNOWLEDGE AND EXPERTISE

- General Management
- Change & Innovation
- Strategic Planning
- Human Resource
- Organization
- Communication
- Presentation
- PR & Branding
- Influence and Persuasion
- Motivation
- Leadership
- Time Management

HONOR / REWARD

- Honored as a Best Employee of the Year by Military Lands & Cantonment.
- Honored for Outstanding Performance by Military Lands & Cantonment.
- Member National Youth Assembly by Government of Pakistan.
- Awarded as a "Best Performer of the Year" 2018. by Lucky Textile Mills Limited.

Savvy Professional · HR & OD, Communication, PR & Branding

A trustworthy conscientious smart-working skilled motivated result-oriented person with 10 years of rich and diversified experience pertaining in the fields of Administration. Human Resource, Marketing and Sales, Education and Development, Organizational Development, Corporate Communication, Public Relations and Branding. Aiming to work for a company that meets my ambitions and maximizes my inner potential. Aspiring to be on a Directorial position in coming 05 years.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lead Corporate Communication, HR & OD - Lucky Textile Mills Ltd, 2017 till Date

Lead Corporate Communication:

- Serving high profile role, fully responsible developing and implementing companywide communication strategy supporting multiple departments in all types of programs execution.
- Leading and implementing standard business process for preparation and approval of announcements and releases through Centralized Communication Zone.
- Compose, revise and proofread corporate communication, marketing materials and branding strategies for the company which include Newsletters, Magazines, Corporate Profile, Corporate Brochures, Videos, resulting in circulation of 5000+ company's magazine.
- Develop, formulate and implement all types of company policies and procedures for 7000
- Responsible to work collectively with all cross-functional departments on all internal and external communications.
- Develop continuous management strategic reports, communication infra-structure, employee engagement activities and communication plans.
- Provide advice and guidance to all high-rank profiles on communication related concerns. Serving as interface with internal and external public while acting as company's spokesperson.

HR & OD:

- Developing employee growth and training plans partnering with Head of HR to create content, and specific management and development programs for 7000 employees. Planning organizational development strategies and implementing change management including organizations restructuring and companywide development initiatives.
- Driving OD projects along with providing guidance, coaching to employees at all levels regarding company's policies, employee motivation, grievance handling specifically 80% of worker staff.
- Supervising the operations of an organization's complete unit payroll with strength of 2700 employees. Administering payroll procedures, ensuring timely processing as well resolving payroll discrep-
- Overseeing the recruitment and hiring responsibilities solely of entire unit. Along with development of competency and growth matrix of said unit.
- Also, an in-house trainer to train management staff on soft skills focused on communication, personal branding, leadership, business etiquettes, harassment, interpersonal skills and so forth.

Head of Assessment (Grade-17) (Contract, Ministry of Defense,

2015 to 2017

- Led 70 direct and 25 indirect staff at Head office. Managed and assessed taxation of 12665 acres' jurisdiction of Cantonment, with total 72000 taxation units.
- Oversaw complete regulatory compliance, strategy formulation, legal matters, and court appeals & hearings.
- Identified and resolved taxpayers' issues, resulting in increase of revenue and retention for the board. As well dealing with employee concerns including performance challenges, grievances, disciplinary action and employee interventions.
- As an additional task, taxed 12,429 shop signboards within the limit of board, generating revenue of 40 M, first time in history of cantonment.

Project Manager (HR & Administration), UNICEF & Govt. of Pakistan 2012 to 2015

- Managed all Human Resource functions of 500 employees on international project of NGO and Govt. of Pakistan.
- Supervised complete recruitment cycle encompassing sourcing, screening, selection and appointment heading to on-boarding, orientation and deputation in different divisions of
- Directed employee training & development and communication programs, compensation and benefits in compliance with set standards by United Nations.
- Administered, transportation and logistics supply to the workforce deputed in 29 districts of
- Oversaw administrative duties on complete project including contract negotiations, vendor selection, legal and regulatory compliance.
- Took various disciplinary action towards absenteeism, late attendance and other misconducts and successfully reduced the same.

QUALIFICATION

- Master in Business Administrative (MBA-HRM)-Mohammad Ali Jinnah University,
- Bachelor in Business Administration (BBA)-University of Karachi.